TARYN L. PATTERSON

Data Analyst Apprentice

Nashville, Tennessee



ABOUT ME

Through my experience working as a Research Specialist, I became familiar with working with large sets of data and realized my interests in Data Analytics. I love being able to make sense of information and use it to help others make informed decisions.

SKILLS

- Excel
- SQL
- PowerBI

- Tableau
- Python
- SalesForce

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Apprentice | *Nashville Software School* | Nashville, TN | July 2021 – Current School offering bootcamp programs focusing on Data Analytics, Data Science, and Coding **Projects:**

- App Trader (SQL) Created an advanced SQL query to pull information and statistics regarding
 App Store and Google Play Store Applications | App Trader Project
- U.S. Hate Crime Data (Tableau) Created an interactive dashboard that provides insights to
 Hate Crimes in the United States using data from the FBI Crime Database | <u>Using Data to Stop</u>
 the Hate
- Central Park Squirrel Census (PowerBI) Created an interactive dashboard that provides insights to the 2018 Central Park Squirrel Census | Central Park Squirrel Census

WORK AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

American Addiction Centers | Brentwood, TN

Company specializing in the treatment of addiction with facilities located across the U.S.

Research and Improvement Specialist, November 2017 - Current

- Point of contact for the company's business offices at our various locations
- Run reports to monitor our business office on specific tasks, such as cash collection, completing patient forms, verifying employment, etc.
- Complete refunds and chargebacks to aid loss prevention
- Create reports and complete projects as instructed by our Director of Billing Practices

Administrative Assistant, January 2017 – November 2017

Support for Treatment Consultants including, but not limited to, booking
flights and cab services, talking with clients interested in treatment, collecting payments,
obtaining information from insurance companies, completing client admissions, and
drafting various paperwork on behalf of the company

Telephone Answering Service, Inc. | Paducah, KY

Call Center servicing local doctors' offices, law offices, hospitals and other regional companies.

Supervising Operator, October 2008 - November 2016 (Intermittent)

- Provided customer service via telephone for over 200 separate accounts
- Supervised and trained other operators and aided them with any questions or problems
- they encountered, while reporting directly to the Vice President of the company.

7 Springs Inn & Suites | Palm Springs, CA

Boutique Hotel

Guest Services Associate, January 2016 - May 2016

- Aided guests and made sure their needs were met in a professional and timely manner
- Assisted guests either in person or over the phone with bookings, spa services, activities, and general information about the area
- Handled any guest complaints or disputes

Palm Springs Chamber of Commerce | Palm Springs, CA

Chamber supporting local businesses and tourism

Executive Assistant, August 2015 – January 2016 (temporary position)

- Front-office point of contact
- Answered all phone calls and responded to emails and requests for information
- Aided the CEO in setting up various Chamber events and saw that they occurred successfully
- Kept all member information correct and up to date using company software

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School (NSS): Nashville, TN | Data Analytics Bootcamp Certification; Anticipated Graduation: January 2022

Murray State University (MSU): Murray, KY | Bachelor of Science, Public Relations, Minor in Sociology; May 2015